Sarah Stone Autograph Collection
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Sarah Stone Autograph Collection 1720-1962
MSS41590
Stone, Sarah, fl. 1840
200 items
1 container
.4 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Resident of Salem, Massachusetts. Letters, clipped signatures, and other autograph items of prominent American and a few British figures, chiefly of the nineteenth century.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848.; Adams, John, 1735-1826.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868.; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1795-1858.; Calhoun, John C. (John Caldwell), 1782-1850.; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852.; Colman, Henry, 1785-1849.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882.; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865.; Grimké, Angelina Emily, 1805-1879.; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894.; Irving, Washington, 1783-1859.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.; Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891.; Madison, James, 1751-1836.; Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908.; Prévost, Augustine, approximately 1725-1786.; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864.; Stone family--Correspondence.; Stone family.; Stone, Sarah, active 1840.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862.; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852.
Subjects
Autographs--Collections.
Places
Salem (Mass.)--History.
Provenance
The autograph collection of Sarah Stone of Salem, Mass., was given to the Library of Congress by Mrs. Ray Morris in 1962
Transfers
A map of the Peninsula between the York and James Rivers, Virginia, circa 1861-1865 have been transferred to the Library's Geography and Map Division where they are identified as part of the Sarah Stone Autograph Collection.
Access and Restrictions
The Sarah Stone Autograph Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The autograph collection of Sarah Stone (fl. 1840) spans the years 1720-1962, with the latest autographed item dating from 1947. The collection contains letters, clipped signatures, and other signed items of prominent American and a few British figures, chiefly of the nineteenth century.
The collection originated with Henry Colman (1785-1849), a Unitarian clergyman and friend of the Stone family, who initiated it with the gift of nineteen items to Sarah Stone in the early 1840s. Colman had received the items mainly in the course of studying agricultural methods in this country and in Europe, including signed letters by George Washington and British General Augustine Prevost during the Revolutionary War. Colman’s correspondents include John Adams, Henry Clay, Edward Everett ( who in 1837 appointed him commissioner to make an agricultural survey of Massachusetts) Angelina Emily Grimké, Benjamin Silliman, James Madison, Daniel Webster, and Martin Van Buren.
Other persons represented include John Quincy Adams, James Buchanan, Benjamin F. Butler, John C. Calhoun, Albert Einstein, Ralph Waldo Emerson, Alexander Hamilton, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Thomas Jefferson, James Russell Lowell, Charles Eliot Norton, and Booker T. Washington. Some letters were received by Sarah Stone herself or by members of her family, who were sailors and ship owners of Salem, Massachusetts, during the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, active in trade with China, Sumatra, and the West Indies. Some were friends of the family of Washington Irving. There are references to Irving in their correspondence as well as one of the author’s letters and a page of a manuscript in his hand.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized chronologically and indexed alphabetically by writer according to a check list of cards received from the donor. Clipped signatures and autographs that are undated or lack the year of creation are grouped together alphabetically in an undated file at the end of the collection.
Container List
- 1720-1799 (Box 1)
- 1800-1819 (Box 1)
- 1820-1828 (Box 1)
- 1830-1839 (Box 1)
- 1840-1846 (Box 1)
- 1851-1866 (Box 1)
- 1873-1894 (Box 1)
- 1903-1947, 1962, including a copy of a letter about the collection and typed transcriptions of other letters (Box 1)
- Undated or no year (Box 1)
  - Clipped signatures (Box 1)
  - Autographs (Box 1)
Index
Abbot, J. E. to Miss ___ Osgood, N.Y., Aug. 19, no year
Adams, John to Henry Colman, 1817, Jan. 13
Adams, John Quincy to ___ Adams [brother], 1818, Nov. 15
Adams, John Quincy to Aaron Bancroft, circa 1825-1829
Adams, John Quincy [clipped signature] undated
Agassiz, Louis [clipped signature], undated
Alexander, John W. to Mrs. ___ Stone, 1886, Feb. 9
Andrew, John A. to Jackson J. Shultze, 1866, Apr. 4
Baird, Spencer Fullerton to ___ Cabot, Jr., 1866, Dec. 18
Barber, Francis to Elias Dayton, 1783, Jan. 23
Baring Bros. & Co. to Robert Stone, 1841, Dec. 11
Barker, Jacob to Benjamin F. Butler, 1824, Jan. 4
Bates, Joshua to unknown, N.Y., June 26, no year
Beck, Lewis C. to Amos Eaton, N.Y., Nov. 24, no year
Beck, Theodric Romeyn to W. C. Little, 1843, Dec.
Bellows, Henry W. to Mrs. ___ Stone, 1876, July 19
Bentley, Dr. ___ Sermon, 1720, Jan. 10
Bentley, William to George A. Ward, 1819, Nov. 29
Bowditch, Nathaniel [clipped signature], undated
Bradford, Alden to Henry Colman, N.Y.
Bradford, William to Francis Brindley, 1794, Jul. 4
Bradford, William to John Mulbone, 1794, Jul. 4
Brazer, John to R. More, 1842, Mar. 14
Bridgman, Laura D. to Mrs. Earnham, N.Y., Dec. 22, no year
Brown-Leguard, C. E. to unknown,, 1864, Sept. 22
Buchanan, James to R. H. Osgood,
Butler, Bejamin F. to Joseph Lancaster, 1838, Mar. 31
Calhoun, John C. to Paul Briggs, Revolutionary War claim, 1819, Jul. 8
Carey, Mathew to Charles R. Webster, 1805, Jul. 18
Carey, Mathew to G. Webster, 1805, Jul. 18
Carey, Mathew to Ebenezer Watson, 1831, Jan. 15
Channing, William Ellery [clipped signature], undated
Chase, William M. to Ellen J. Stone, 1884, Jan. 15 (25)
Church, Frederick E. [clipped signature], undated
Clarkson, Thomas, General Anti-Slavery Convention, printed resolutions, 1840, Jan.
Clay, Henry to Henry Colman, 1842, Mar. 4
Cleveland, Lucy H., "Asperations," poem, undated
Cleveland, Lucy H., "O! That the brightness.. .," poem, 1841, Dec. 27
Colman, Henry to Sarah Stone, 1841, Dec. 30
Colman, Henry to Sarah Stone, 1842, Dec. 27
Colman, Henry to Sarah Stone, undated
Colquhun, Patrick to Benjamin Walker, 1793, Nov.
Curtis, Edward to George Bush, 1841, Jul. 26
Cushing, Caled [clipped signature], undated
Cutler, Manasseh to John Stone, 1814, Nov. 8
Dallas, Alexander J. to unknown, 1815, Apr. 24
Dane, William, selectman of Gloucester, 1804, Mar. 10
Day, James, selectman of Gloucester, 1804, Mar. 10
Dearborn, Henry [clipped signature], undated
DeWitt, Simeon to Amos Eaton, 1827, Jan. 25
Dudley, Charles E. to Thomas Wolcott, 1830, Dec. 25
Eaton, Peter to unknown, undated
Einstein, Albert to unknown, 1947, Jan. 15
Elwell, Isacc, selectman of Gloucester, 1804, Mar. 10
Emerson, Ralph Waldo [clipped signature], undated
Everett, Edward to Henry Colman, 1837, Dec. 18
Farrar, Mrs. ___ to Henry Colman, NY., Dec. 24, no year
Fitzsimons, Thomas to Messrs. LeRov and Bayard, 1789, Jan. 29
Frémont, John C. [clipped signature], undated
Goodale, Grace to Mrs. ___ Grinnell, 1930, Apr. 27
Goodale, Grace to Mrs. ___ Grinnell, 1930, Apr. 27
Goodhue, B. [clipped signature], undated
Goodrich, S. G. to R. S. H. George, 1842, Mar.
Gould, Hannah Flagg to Mrs. D. R. White, undated
Gould, Hannah Flagg, "But Christ hath slumbered," poem, undated
Greeley, Horace, autograph, 1866, Nov. 3
Grimké, Angelina Emily to Henry Colman, undated
Hale, Edward Everett to William H. Bogart, 1878, Nov. 7
Hale, Edward Everett to Mrs. ___ Stone, 1894, Oct. 15
Hamilton, Alexander to Joseph Whipple, 1793, Apr. 15
Hamilton, James A. to Benjamin F. Butler, 1818, Apr. 2
Lesley, J. to William E. Warren, receipt, 1861, Nov. 19
Harper, Robert Goodloe to John Henry, 1801, Aug. 23
Heath, William. to Edward Wheeler, pay order for Livingston & Gordon
Higginson, Thomas W. [clipped signature], undated
Hitchcock, Edward to Henry Colman, 1840, Dec. 31
Hoffman, Josiah Ogden to Stephen Van Rensselear, 1819, Apr. 25
Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Build the more stately mansions.. ., poem, 1863, Aug. 13
Holmes, Oliver Wendell to L. L. Goodie, 1873, Jan. 1
Holmes, Oliver Wendell, "Please admit the Bearer" [clipped signature], undated
Holyoke, Edward to Francis Bernard, memorial, 1766, Feb. 7
Holyoke, Edward A. [clipped signature], undated
Howe, Samuel Gridley to Mrs. — Cabot, receipt, 1863, Jan. 31
Howell, William T. to Jane Elizabeth Robbins, cover, 1903, Dec. 11
Howells, William Dean [clipped signature], undated
Hoover, Herbert to Sarah Stone, 1920, Dec. 27
Humphrey, H. to Henry Colman, 1842, Jan. 14
Irving, Washington to William H. Bogart, 1851, Feb. 23
Irving, Washington Columbus, fragment, undated
Jackson, James to H. O. Stone, N.Y., Oct. 30, no year
James, G. V. B. to Washington Irving, 1880, Dec.
Jefferson, Thomas to John Adams, 1818, Nov. 13
Jefferson, Thomas [clipped signature], undated
Johnson, Samuel [clipped signature], undated
Kendall, H. L. to J. Maury Garland receipt, 1861, Nov. 11
La Farge, John to Ellen J. Stone, 1895, Dec. 17
Laffitte, J. Co. to Messrs LeRoy & Bayard, 1826, Sep. 5
Langdon, John to Messrs LeRoy & Bayard, 1823, Jan. 10
Lawrence, Abbott, autograph, undated
Lawrence, John to Benjamin Walker, 1809, May 22
Le Braz, Anatole to unknown, 1907, Mar. 25
Lee, Charles to Messrs Le Roy & Bayard, 1791, Sept. 17
Lee, Isaac to Mrs. S. Dunlap, 1843, Jan. 2
Lee, Light-Horse Harry to John Fitzgerald, 1792, Jan. 28
Lesley, J. to William E. Warren, receipt, 1861, Nov. 19
Lewis, Morgan to unknown, 1813, Jul. 23
Lincoln, Levi to unknown [illegible], 1828, Sept. 22
Lincoln, Levi [clipped signature], undated
Livingston, Peter R. to unknow, 1782, Aug. 25
Lowell, James Russell to Kate Stone, 1885, Nov. 20
Lowell, John, consent, undated
Madison, James to Jacob Crowninshield, 1805, Jul. 3
Madison, James to Henry Colman, 1817, Mar. 5
Madison, James [clipped signature], undated
Matthews, Brander to Society for Protecting Italian Immigrants, N.Y., Dec. 13, no year
McKinley, John [Governor of Delaware], return of officers, circa 1776
Meigs, Return Jonathan, Jr., to William Burke, 1822, Jun. 19
Miller, James [clipped signature], undated
Mitchell, Donald G. [clipped signature], undated
Mitchell, James to Daniel H. Barnes, 1824, Aug. 4
Monroe, James [clipped signature], undated
Morris, Jacob to Messrs LeRoy & Bayard, 1820, Jul. 22
Morris, Thomas to John V. Henry, 1794, Aug. 29
Morse, John T. to Edward Jackson, 1890, Oct. 8
Morton, Marcus to John Hawes, 1820, Dec. 17
Norton, Charles Eliot to Society for Protection of Italian Immigrants, 1903, Dec. 14
Palfrey, John Graham to unknown, 1841, May 10
Peel, Robert [clipped signature], undated
Peters, Richard to P. Van Rensselaer, 1780, Jan. 5
Phillips, Vendell to Mrs. D. Cabot, 1863, Jan. 7
Pickering, Timothy [clipped signature], undated
Pickering, Wendell [clipped signature], undated
Platt, Jonas to John V. Henry, 1816, Nov. 28
Poinsett, Joel Roberts to William H. Seward, 1840, Apr. 30
Porter, Peter B. to Thomas W. Olcott, 1822, Aug. 13
Porter, Peter B. to Thomas W. Olcott, 1824, Jul. 30
Potter, Alonso to Henry Colman, 1842, Nov. 30
Prescott, William to Robert Stone, receipt, 1806, Jun. 9
Prescott, William to Henry Colman, 1841, May 7
Prescott, William Hickling to William Frederick Harnden, 1843, Jul. 30
Prescott, William Hickling to Messrs. Harnden & Co., 1845, May 30
Prevost, Augustine to Benjamin Lincoln, 1780, Jan. 11
Prince, John to John Stone, undated
Putnam, Samuel [clipped signature], undated
Quincy, Josiah et al. to ___ Stone, undated
Randolph, Edmund Jennings to James Monroe, 1795, Jul. 21
Renner, Baron ___ to Henry Colman, 1837, Nov. 10
Rodney, Caesar to Thomas Rodney, 1775, June 4
Rothschild, Nathan Mever to Messrs Harnden & Co., 1844, Apr. 3
Rowland & Shriver to Capt.___ Waller, 1861, Dec. 31
Rowland & Shriver see also Shriver, J. M.
Safonoff, W. to unknown, 1907, Mar. 10
Sargent, Lucius M. to Thomas C. Smith, 1864, Dec. 26
Sartain, William to Sarah Stone, 1903, Dec. 13
Schuyler, Philip John to Myndert P. Vosburgh, 1800, Jan. 3
Scott, Walter [clipped signature], undated
Sedgwick, Catherine María to Henry Colman, 1836, Jun. 30
Seward, William H. to Henry C. Webb, 1839, Jan. 11
Seward, William H. to William C. Marcy, 1842, May 26
Shaw, Lemuel et al. to ___ Stone, undated [See Quincy, Josiah, undated]
Shriver, J. M. to Capt. ___ Waller, 1861, Dec. 27
Shriver, J. M. to Capt. ___ Morris, 1862, Jan. 10
Shriver, J. M. See also Rowland & Shriver
Silliman, Benjamin to Henry Colman, 1840, Jul 25
Silsbee, Nathaniel to R. Stone, 1828, Oct. 18
Smith, Nathaniel to Nathan Smith, 1810, May 17
Stanton, Edwin McMasters [clipped signature], undated
Stewart, Charles to Messrs. LeRoy & Bayard, 1823, Nov. 17
Story, Joseph et al. to ___ Stone, undated [See Quincy, Josiah, undated]
Tateish, Onojero [clipped signature], undated
Taylor, John to Col. ___ Walker, 1799, Mar. 20
Taylor, John W. to William Gould, 1818, Nov. 26
Teynham, Lord ___, pass for House of Lords, 1838, June 19
Thayer, Abbott Handerson to Ellen J. Stone, 1876, June 29
Thayer, Abbott Handerston to Ellen J. Stone, 1886, Oct. 19
Throop, Enos Thompson to Abraham Van Vechten, 1820, Nov. 13
Tompkins, Dainel D.to Archibald McIntyre, 1812, Oct. 16
Torrey, John to Amos Eaton, 1819, Jun. 4
Trower, J. R. to William E. Warren, receipt, 1861, Dec. 19
Trumbull, Jonathan to unknown, 1782, May 24
Tuckerman, Joseph to Henry Colman, 1838, Aug. 18
Upham, Charles W. to F. Stone, 1830, May 22
Van Buren, Martin to Henry Colman, 1838, Apr. 17
Van Ness, William Peter to unknown, 1816, Jul. 6
Vaughan, T. W. to Henry Colman, 1836, Jul. 2
Wadsworth, Jeremiah to Nehemiah Hubbard, 1739, Oct. 25
Washington, Booker T. to Annie Stone, undated
Washington, George to unknown, 1777, May 25
Webb, Laura to Miss Maggie [unknown], 1859, Dec. 4
Webster, Daniel to Henry Colman, 1836, May 25
Wheelock, John to ___ Mcclure, 1780, Jun. 28
Wheelock, John to Levi Har, 1782, Nov. 11
Whitfield, J. F. to H. M. Waller, 1862, Mar. 13
Viggin, Kate Douglas [clipped signature], undated
Willett, Mariaus to ___ Dean, 1778, May 9
Willis, Nathaniel Parker to F. Alexander, undated
Wilson, Christine [clipped signature], undated
Wilson, James Grant to Mrs. Irving, 1885, Aug. 18
Winter, Robert [clipped signature], undated
Winthrop, Robert C. to Harnden & Co., 1845, Jun. 14
Wolcott, Oliver [clipped signature], undated
Woodbury, Levi to Mrs. ___ Dunlap et al., 1842, Oct. 24
Woodworth, Samuel [clipped signature], undated
Wright, Silas to Stephen Van Rensselaer, 1833, May 13
Yates, Peter W. to Leonard Gansevoort, 1808, Feb. 23
Yates, Robert to Gerard Banker, undated